{"tossups": [{"question": "In this novel, a woman\u2019s passionate letters to her indifferent daughter Clara are so well-written that they are taught in schools after the woman\u2019s death. That woman\u2019s companion and maid to the Marquesas was raised at the (*) Convent of Santa Maria Rosa de la Rosas, where the protagonist of part three of this novel was abandoned with his twin, Manuel. In this novel, that twin falls in love with Camila Perichole. Her son and valet fall to their death with Pepita, Esteban, and the Marquesa de Montemayor in, for 10 points, what Thornton Wilder novel in which the namesake Peruvian structure collapses?", "answer": "The Bridge of San Luis Rey", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One poem from this country claims that \u201cBetween my finger and my thumb, the squat pen rests\u201d and that the narrator will undergo the title action with it. Death of a Naturalist is a poetry collection from this country that includes the poem \u201cDigging.\u201d (*) One line in a poem from this country claims that a beast \u201cSlouches towards Bethlehem to be born,\u201d and that poem is The Second Coming. For 10 points, name this country, home to poets such as Seamus Heaney and William Butler Yeats.", "answer": "Ireland", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Ginzburg v. United States ruled that the intent of the seller determines whether this quality exists. The acronym SLAPS refers to a three-pronged test used to evaluate whether this is present, which was derived from the case Miller v. California. Dollree Mapp was charged with possessing objects with this quality. The quote \u201cI (*) know it when I see it\u201d was used by Potter Stewart to describe this thing in the case Jacobellis v. Ohio. That case involved the illegal screening of the film, The Lovers. For 10 points, name this type of content that includes swearing and other morally repulsive acts and words?", "answer": "Obscenity [accept specific forms of obscenity such as pornography, swearing, etc. before \u201cswearing\u201d is mentioned]", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "The fountain of the Piazza Farnese was believed to have been repurposed from one of these places. A section of one of these structures was converted into the Basilica of Saint Mary of the Angels and the Martyrs in 1563. One of these places located behind the Caelian Hill was used as a burial mound for pilgrims after Vitiges\u2019 capture of Rome. Visitors to these buildings would (*) undress in an apodyterium, and these buildings contained a frigidarium, tepidarium, and caldarium, which each varied in water temperature. For 10 points, name these buildings where Romans would often cleanse themselves.", "answer": "Roman public baths [accept thermae or balnae; accept specific baths such as the Baths of Caracalla or Baths of Diocletian]", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Only one eukaryote, monocercomonoides, is known to completely lack this organelle. Ragged red fibers on a Gomori stain show a disease of this organelle, and porins exist in the outer membrane of this maternally inherited organelle that contains its own unique DNA. (*) Hypotheses speculate these organelles may have developed through endosymbiosis. This organelle self-replicates during mitosis and meiosis and has folds called cristae that increase surface area for chemical reactions to take place. For 10 points, name this organelle where ATP is generated during cellular respiration, leading to this organelle\u2019s nickname, the \u201cpowerhouse of the cell.\u201d", "answer": "Mitochondria [accept Mitochondrion]", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The only woman in this painting blocks her face with her left hand. The artist of this painting is depicted in the background below three shadowy rows of figures, holding onto a railing. His signature appears in the bottom right on the front of a table. The darkness of the room alludes to the (*) unhygienic medical practices at the time, in stark contrast with a later painting by the same artist which depicts Dr. David Hayes Agnew. For 10 points, name this painting depicting a femoral surgery being performed at Jefferson Medical College, a work by Thomas Eakins.", "answer": "The Gross Clinic", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "On this day, God writes each adherent\u2019s fate for the coming year in the Book of Life but does not close that book until a later holiday, making that decision permanent. This two day celebration begins on the first of Tishrei, and begins the \u201cDays of Awe,\u201d which end on the tenth of Tishrei, also called (*) Yom Kippur. During this celebration, the shofar, a ram\u2019s horn, is blown one hundred times, and adherents eat apples and honey. For 10 points, name this first of the High Holy Days, the Jewish New Year.", "answer": "Rosh Hashanah [accept Yom Teruah]", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "One piece named for this country begins with pizzicato C\u2019s and is often described as \u201ca piece in F and nothing more\u201d by its composer Emmanuel Chabrier. The violin solo \u201cZigeunerweisen,\u201d or \u201cGypsy Airs,\u201d is by a composer from this country, and another violin solo named \u201cSymphony This Country\u201d is by Edouard Lalo. Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov wrote a (*) \u201cCapriccio\u201d named after this country that contains two similar \u201cAlborada\u201d movements. For 10 points, name this country home to Manuel de Falla and Isaac Albeniz, the latter of which composed a work titled \u201cIberia.\u201d", "answer": "Spain [accept Espa\u00f1a]", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In one work by this man, Felipe Montero stumbles upon the title character expressionlessly beheading a goat in the kitchen. In that same work, Montero falls asleep for an indeterminate amount of time and when he wakes, makes love to the title character. In addition to (*) Aura, this author wrote a novel that is told through the flashbacks of an unnamed female character, who is presumed to be Harriet Winslow. For 10 points, name this creator of General Tomas Arroyo and Se\u00f1ora Consuelo, the author of The Old Gringo and The Death of Artemio Cruz.", "answer": "Carlos Fuentes", "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Voigt notation can be used to express this law in a six-by-six matrix. This law was generalized to three dimensions by Cauchy. Young\u2019s modulus multiplied by cross-sectional area over length is equal to this law\u2019s force constant. This law begins to break down at the (*) elastic limit. The proportionality constant of this law has units of Newtons per meter, and objects obeying this law are an example of simple harmonic motion. For 10 points, name this governing law of simple two-dimensional springs, which states that the restorative force acting on a spring is negative and proportional to the displacement from equilibrium, or that F equals negative kx.", "answer": "Hooke\u2019s Law", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "[Two Answers Required] During a battle that was fought between these two countries, the Kwantung Army was decimated by the other side\u2019s army at Khalkhin Gol. A conflict between these two countries featured engagements at Mukden. (*) Theodore Roosevelt helped to end that war by negotiating the Treaty of Portsmouth. That war also saw the Battle of Tsushima Straits. These two countries currently dispute ownership of the Kuril Islands. For 10 points, name these two countries that fought a war from 1904-1905 under the leaderships of Emperor Meiji and Nicholas II.", "answer": "Russia and Japan [accept either order; accept Russo-Japanese War]", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One story from the mythology of these people involves the murder of four hundred boys by a vengeful god they attempt to kill. Another story from these people involves a demon who proclaimed himself to be both the sun and the moon, who is defeated with a (*) blowgun and stripped of his power. During that encounter, Seven-Macaw tears off one of the arms of Hunahpu, one of the two Hero Twins of this culture\u2019s mythology. For 10 points, name these people whose mythology is recorded extensively in the Popul Vuh.", "answer": "Mayans", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "During this battle, Station HYPO cracked the losing side\u2019s encryption. This battle notably did not see the participation of the Sh\u014dkaku and Zuikaku because of damages sustained a month earlier. This battle saw the United States sink the Akagi and (*) three other carriers, while it lost only the USS Yorktown. Ishikoro Yamamoto\u2019s crushing defeat at the hands of Chester Nimitz at this battle left the Imperial Japanese Navy incapacitated. For 10 points, name this 1942 battle decisively won by the United States Navy, the turning point of the Pacific Theatre.", "answer": "Battle of Midway", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of these events takes place at Apartment 50 on Walpurgis Night where a character is lured by the offer of becoming a witch. A newly crowned character arrives at another one of these events and shakes the (*) Red Queen before placing the Red King into checkmate and waking up. A Katherine Mansfield story is titled (**) \u201cA Garden\u201d variety of this event that is overshadowed by the death of the Sheridans\u2019 working-class neighbor. For 10 points, name this title event of Harold Pinter\u2019s story about a birthday celebration for Stanley.", "answer": "Party [accept Birthday Party; accept Ball before (**)]", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "On this TV show, an elderly woman unwittingly asks out a priest she meets during physical therapy, and that woman is an illegal immigrant from Venezuela. That woman\u2019s daughter had the title character when she was sixteen with her later husband, the telenovela star of (*) The Passions of Santos, Rogelio de la Vega. During season three, a part of the title of this CW series is crossed out after the title character marries her detective boyfriend, Michael Cordero, Jr. For 10 points, name this show on which the title character is accidentally artificially inseminated.", "answer": "Jane the Virgin", "subcategory": "Trash Television", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "Though not a black hole, BICEP2 was used to find primordial gravitational waves in this entity. Unevenness in this entity was explained by redshift in the Sachs-Wolfe effect. Particles in this entity can undergo scattering to higher energies as a result of inverse Compton scattering in the Sunyaev-Zel\u2019dovich effect. This entity is a (*) \u201crelic\u201d from the creation of the universe and shows evidence for the Big Bang. This entity was discovered at Bell Labs by Penzias and Wilson and has a temperature of 2.7 degrees Kelvin. For 10 points, name this radiation source left over from the Big Bang.", "answer": "Cosmic Microwave Background Radiation [accept CMBR or CMB]", "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Different schools of thought about this practice in the Islamic world disagree on the validity of qiyas, or reasoning from \u201canalogy.\u201d Alan Dershowitz argued that the modern incarnation of this practice, as found in the west, stems from Old Testament tradition. The United States and the United Kingdom notably use the \u201ccommon\u201d (*) version of this practice, whereas most of the world adheres to its \u201ccivil\u201d formulation. For 10 points, identify this practice of creating and enforcing rules that regulate social behavior.", "answer": "Law", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "One compound that has this color has a seven to eighteen ratio between its central metal and the bonding ligand, and that same compound was believed to be two different materials, one of which is named for Turnbull. The 2014 Nobel Prize was awarded for creating a diode of this color. A coordination complex containing iron and cyanide is known as (*) Prussian [this color]. Indicators, such as litmus paper, turn this color upon the presence of a base, and a variety of corundum called sapphire is this color. For 10 points, name this color that describes elements such as indium and cobalt.", "answer": "Blue", "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s book, The Army of the Future, stressed the utility of armored divisions and combined arms in future warfare. This man supported a North American domestic terrorist organization during a speech where he stated (*) \u201cVive le Quebec libre!\u201d at Montreal\u2019s Expo 67. This right-wing President gained prominence with speeches where he opposed Philippe Petain and Vichy France during World War II. For 10 points, name this first president of the Fifth Republic in France and leader of Free France during World War II, a decorated French general.", "answer": "Charles Andr\u00e9 Joseph Marie de Gaulle", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This building was nicknamed \u201cRising Mildew\u201d because of its constant leaking. The Vandamm Residence in North by Northwest was inspired by this building. Mendel Glickman and William Peters helped design this structure and had also constructed the columns of its architect\u2019s earlier (*) Johnson Wax Building. This building used a T-shape, as well as a cantilever, in order to stabilize itself on the north bank of Bear Run. For 10 points, name this house in Mill Run, Pennsylvania that was designed for the Kaufmann family by Frank Lloyd Wright.", "answer": "Fallingwater [accept Kaufmann Residence before \u201cKaufmann\u201d is mentioned] Tiebreaker", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This artist painted a woman in pink balancing a basket of the title food on her head in his painting The Shrimp Girl. A palette with the phrase \u201cThe Line of Beauty\u201d sits next to this artist\u2019s dog Trump in his painting The Painter and the Pug. The Earl Squanderfield walks into a bagnio to find his lover and Silvertongue in a painting from this artist\u2019s (*) Marriage-a-la-mode series. A painting series by this man shows a rich merchant ending up in Fleet Debtor\u2019s Prison after he rejects Sarah Young\u2019s hand in marriage. For 10 points, name this English painter of A Rake\u2019s Progress.", "answer": "William Hogarth Packet 11 \u2013 Bonuses", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "The crew of the <em>Aurora</em> mutinied during this event and fired a shot at the Winter Palace to signal its beginning. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["October Revolution [accept Great October Socialist Revolution or Red October]", "Vladimir Ilyich Lenin", "New Economic Policy"], "parts": ["Name this revolution which saw the Bolsheviks overthrow Alexander Kerensky\u2019s provisional government. John Reed documented this event in his book Ten Days that Shook the World.", "This head of the Bolsheviks led the October Revolution. He sent his subordinates to sign the Treaty of Brest-Litovsk with Germany, and he authored the April Theses while in exile in Switzerland. He was succeeded by Joseph Stalin.", "Lenin introduced this economic plan that introduced \u201cstate capitalism\u201d to the Soviet Union. It abolished forced grain requisition but it also led to the Scissors Crisis when a huge gap between industrial and agricultural prices formed."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "We are living in a material world, so for 10 points each, answer some questions about precious metals and their applications in chemistry.", "answer": ["Gold", "Platinum", "Palladium"], "parts": ["This metal is used extensively in electronics because of its high conductivity and low reactivity. It was used as the target in the experiment that proved the existence of the nucleus.", "This metal is used as a catalyst in modern catalytic converters, thereby reducing the production of carbon monoxide. This metal is frequently used in its black form to catalyze organic reactions.", "This metal is closely related to platinum, and its acetate is frequently used to catalyze organic reactions. This element was more famously used in Fleischmann and Pons\u2019s \u201ccold fusion\u201d reactor to electrically break down deuterium."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This musical pairs the contrasting songs \u201cEpiphany\u201d and \u201cA Little Priest\u201d together at the end of Act 1. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street", "Stephen Sondheim", "Broadway"], "parts": ["Name this musical that features the murderous \u201cDemon Barber of Fleet Street,\u201d who has his victims baked into Mrs. Lovett\u2019s pies.", "This prolific American composer and lyricist wrote the lyrics to West Side Story in addition to Sweeney Todd.", "Sondheim\u2019s early work, including his contributions to West Side Story, found success in this popular theatre in Manhattan that performs many musicals."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "This philosopher argued that because \u201cGod is an absolutely perfect being,\u201d then we can only do service to God by admiring his work in his <em>Discourse on Metaphysics</em>. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz", "Happiness [accept word forms]", "Monads"], "parts": ["Name this philosopher, who is probably most famous for developing calculus independent of Isaac Newton.", "Leibniz believed that God is only concerned with preserving this concept within his subjects, concurring with his statement of \u201cWe live in the best of all possible worlds.\u201d Utilitarians strive to maximize this concept among people.", "Leibniz envisioned these indivisible entities that control all natural phenomena and people. The most powerful one of these entities controls the soul."], "category": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "Lucy Steele announces her engagement to Mr. Ferrars in this work only to discover that he is in love with one of the main characters. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Sense and Sensibility", "John Willoughby [accept either]", "Jane Austen"], "parts": ["Identify this novel that focuses on Mrs. Dashwood and her daughters Elinor, Marianne, and Margaret.", "In Sense and Sensibility, this man rescues Marianne after she twists her ankle running down the hills of Barton; this man then abandons her in favor of the wealthier Sophia Grey.", "This author of Sense and Sensibility also wrote Emma and Mansfield Park."], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer some questions about a time when Gaia tried to destroy Olympus. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Typhon", "Mount Etna", "Echidna"], "parts": ["This snake-like monster was the spawn of Gaia and Tartarus, intended to overthrow Zeus. Upon his first arrival at Olympus, the Olympians turned to animals and fled, but he was eventually defeated by Zeus with the aid of thunderbolts.", "In many variants of Zeus\u2019s clash with Typhon, he ultimately traps the monster under this mountain, explaining its volcanic nature.", "This half snake \u201cMother of Monsters\u201d is the mate of Typhon and mother of Cerberus, the Lernaean Hydra, the Sphinx, Scylla, and the Nemean Lion according to various sources. In modern times, her name has been given to an order of anteaters."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "When this party\u2019s most notable member resigned in 2016, its only MP, Douglas Carswell, tweeted a smiling emoji. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["United Kingdom Independence Party", "Brexit [accept descriptions of Britain leaving the European Union]", "Lisbon"], "parts": ["Name this Eurosceptic British party, symbolized by the Pound Sterling, led until 2016 by Nigel Farage. Though as of 2017 it holds no seats in the House of Commons, this party holds the most seats in the European Parliament of any British party.", "This action was the primary goal of UKIP and was accomplished after an upset victory in a 2016 referendum. Teresa May suffered a blow to her plans for a \u201chard\u201d version of this action following the June 2017 election.", "In March 2017, Teresa May triggered Article 50 of a treaty named for this city. That treaty, named for this Iberian city, was ratified in 2007 to build on treaties of Amsterdam and Nice, and it outlined the procedure for leaving the E.U."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points, answer some questions regarding tariffs in American history.", "answer": ["William McKinley", "Hawley-Smoot Tariff [accept Smoot-Hawley Tariff]", "World Trade Organization"], "parts": ["When this man was a U.S. Senator, he drafted a namesake tariff that raised import duties to almost fifty percent. While running for president, this man defeated a candidate who ran on the \u201cfree silver\u201d platform, William Jennings Bryan.", "This tariff passed during Herbert Hoover\u2019s administration raised import duties to the second-highest level ever in American history. It is considered to be a main cause of the Great Depression.", "After the United States joined this international economic organization, it adopted a policy of low tariffs. This organization was created by the Marrakech Agreement, and its predecessor was the GATT."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about techniques used in calculus.", "answer": ["Integration [accept word forms]", "Integration by parts", "Disk method [accept Washer method]"], "parts": ["Riemann sums are used to approximate this operation that is used to find the area under a curve and is the opposite of differentiation.", "Derived from the product rule for differentiation, this method of integration can be used to find the antiderivative of x times e to the x.", "Like the shell method, this technique is used to find the volume of an area between two functions rotated around an axis. Unlike the shell method, this method integrates parallel to the axis of rotation."], "subcategory": "Science Math", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Weird names can be as memorable and significant as visible deformities. For 10 points each, name these works with protagonists with names a little out of the ordinary.", "answer": ["A Christmas Carol", "Lolita", "Song of Solomon"], "parts": ["Ebenezer Scrooge\u2019s name is a direct reference to his personality in this Charles Dickens\u2019 holiday novella.", "Even though he\u2019s a pedophile obsessed with nymphets, Humbert Humbert\u2019s name still inspires pity in readers of this Vladimir Nabokov novel.", "In this Toni Morrison novel, daughters of the Dead family are named by placing a pin randomly in the Bible, resulting in Milkman\u2019s sisters being called \u201cFirst Corinthians\u201d and \u201cMagdalene called Lena.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "In 1996, this country\u2019s military shot down aircrafts conducting anti-government broadcasts sponsored by Brothers to the Rescue. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Cuba", "Eli\u00e1n Gonz\u00e1lez", "Attorney General"], "parts": ["Name this communist Caribbean state led by the Castro brothers since 1959. Numerous citizens have risked their lives to sail ninety miles north to Florida from this nation.", "One famous incident involving Cuban refugees surrounded this child. In 2000, he was, against the wishes of his mother\u2019s Miami relatives, sent back to his father in Cuba.", "The first female holder of this position, Janet Reno, ordered that Gonzalez be sent back to Cuba. Earlier in Reno\u2019s time in this position, controversy surrounded the ATF and FBI, which are overseen by it."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "There is nothing new under the sun - authors consciously draw upon religious traditions for inspiration and symbolism. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Ecclesiastes", "Solomon", "Torah"], "parts": ["Name this book of the Old Testament often mined for ominous sounding proverbs. It decries the apparent meaningless of life and ends with \u201cFear God, and keep his commandments.\u201d", "The author of c refers to himself as the son of David, King in Jerusalem. This means that he is probably this great King of Israel who built the first temple but offended God, who split his kingdom.", "Ecclesiastes is one of twenty-four books that makes up the central texts of Judaism, often referred to by this name."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "This amino acid works via a negative feedback cycle. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Tryptophan [accept Trp]", "Escherichia Coli", "Polymerase"], "parts": ["Name this amino acid that was the first repressible operon discovered and is symbolized W.", "Tryptophan was found in these bacteria and is associated with food contamination. These gram negative bacteria are normally present in the gut but can also come from eating raw foods.", "The tryptophan repressor works by repressing this enzyme. The DNA version of this enzyme is used in DNA replication to synthesize DNA from nucleotides."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, name these architectural features of Gothic cathedrals.", "answer": ["Nave", "Flying buttresses [prompt on partial answer]", "Stained glass [prompt on partial answer]"], "parts": ["This is the central hall of the cathedral and houses the congregation. It has aisles along either side and is separated from them with rows of pillars.", "In order to support the verticality of Gothic cathedrals, these supports were created in order stabilize the structure. They connect the wall of the cathedral to a pier on the outside without touching the ground.", "Because of external supports, such as flying buttresses, the walls of Gothic cathedrals are opened up for decoration. The large windows of cathedrals are typically made out of this colored substance."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This author\u2019s novel <em>No Country for Old Men</em> was adapted into a film of the same name. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Cormac McCarthy", "Meteor showers", "The Road"], "parts": ["Name this author who wrote about a group of scalp hunters in Blood Meridian.", "The kid in Blood Meridian is born during one of these events, and it is implied that he is killed by the Judge during an event of this kind.", "Cormac McCarthy also wrote this post-apocalyptic book, about the journey of a man and his son to the sea."], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This nation declared independence under the leadership of Kwame Nkrumah. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Ghana", "Asante Kingdom", "Ivory"], "parts": ["Name this west-African country formerly known as the Gold Coast. A member of the Non-Aligned Movement, it followed its own path of socialist development.", "Ghana was home to this famously resilient nation-state that fought several wars with the British over their sacred golden stool. It technically still exists as a constitutionally protected proto-state.", "Despite being centered in the Gold Coast, the Asante state was also famous for the trade of this material taken from the tusks of African elephants."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "South America is home to diverse flora and fauna. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Amazon rainforest", "Llama [accept Lama glama]", "Gran Chaco [accept Chaco Plain]"], "parts": ["One of the most biodiverse regions on earth is this rainforest, the largest in the world. One in ten species lives in this rainforest.", "This camelid species is native to the Andes Mountains in western South America. This domesticated animal was, unlike the alpaca, commonly used to transport goods through the mountains before the arrival of Europeans.", "This lowland region is mainly located in Bolivia, Paraguay, and Argentina. Plants and animals in this region, such as the Southern three-banded armadillo, have adapted to the arid climate of this region."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "This artist painted <em>The Origin of the World</em>. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Gustave Courbet", "Jean-Francois Millet", "Barbizon school"], "parts": ["Name this artist, who, in another work, showed a cardinal in white carrying a wooden cross while a cardinal in black performs the dutiful rites in his work A Burial at Ornans.", "Another painter who liked to paint French outdoor scenes was this man, who showed three women picking ears of corn in The Gleaners. Salvador Dali analyzed whether the subjects of his The Angelus were mourning a dead child.", "Along with Theodore Rousseau and others, Jean-Francois Millet was a member of this French realist school whose members painted in the namesake town near the Fontainbleau Forest."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This quantity has the same units as work. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Torque", "Moment of inertia", "Mass"], "parts": ["Sometimes written as force times radius, name this rotational analogue of force.", "Torque can also be written as the product of angular acceleration and this quantity that can be found using the parallel axis theorem.", "Moment of inertia can be written as the integral of r squared with respect to this other variable, of which moment of inertia is the rotational analogue of."], "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This poetry collection was translated into <em>Song Offerings</em>. For 10 points each:", "answer": ["Gitanjali", "Rabindranath Tagore", "National Anthems"], "parts": ["Name this set of one hundred three poems, of which fifty were from the drama Achalayatan. The thirty-fifth poem from this collection states \u201cWhere the mind is without fear and the head is held high.\u201d", "This South Asian poet wrote Gitanjali. This Kolkatan was the first non-European to win the Nobel Prize in Literature.", "Tagore penned two of these specific compositions. One of those works is entitled \u201cJana Gana Mana\u201d and ends with a line translated as \u201cvictory, victory, victory to thee.\u201d Another example of these works is \u201cGod Save the Queen.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}]}